Guide to the Yasser Alwan Collection 1890-1970 AD.MC.002
AbuDhabi
- Series II: Egypt, 1895-1971 (Box 1-7)
  - A group portrait of five women with three children standing in front of an open door (linked ref1413). 14 x 9cm, 14 June 1931; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Buildings; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Greek Writing; Group Portraits; Houses; Photographic Prints; Women
  - Portrait of a woman lying down on a bed of flowers and branches. Two children visible in the background (linked ref1412). 9 x 14cm, 14 June 1931; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Bathing Suits / Swimsuits; Buildings; Children; Egypt; Gelatin Silver Prints; Greek Writing; Houses; Individual Portraits; Photographic Prints; Women
  - A group portrait of men posing with violins and an oud. 20.0 x 25.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Doors; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Musical Instruments; Musicians; Oud; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography
  - A group portrait of men wearing suits and tarbouches, posing in a room with various pictures hanging on the wall. 24.0 x 30.1 cm, Undated; Studio ? Nadir, Alexandrie (Egypt); Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Bow Ties; Boys; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A group portrait of four men, three in a vehicle with a pyramid and sphinx behind them. 28.9 x 34.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Cars; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Giza, Egypt; Group Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Police; Pyramids of Giza; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Transportation; Travel; Uniforms
  - A group portrait of fourteen women in a courtyard. 30.4 x 36.2 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Buildings; Egypt; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Head Covers; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A group portrait of men and one woman, four men wear white overalls and the woman wears a nurse's veil. 35.8 x 42.2cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Architecture; Buildings; Doctors; Doors; Fezes / Tarbouches; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Nurses; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits; Traditional Dress; Uniforms; Women
  - A group portrait of doctors and nurses in front of a building, sandbags line the collonade. 35.8 x 42.4 cm, 1940; Studio Roy, Alexandria, Egypt (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Alexandria, Egypt; Arabic Writing; Architecture; Buildings; Cars; Gelatin Silver Prints; Group Portraits; Men; Nurses; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Uniforms; Women
  - A series of five individual portraits of men and young men. Second photo shows two people, and third is tinted red. 18.9 x 53.7 cm, Undated; Studio Photo Ramses, Cairo, Egypt (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Boys; Cairo, Egypt; Cigarettes; Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Photographic Prints; Smoking; Studio Photography
  - A series of five individual portraits of women. 20.0 x 53.7 cm, Undated; Studio Vincent Photo Egyptienne, Rue Abdine No. 6, Caire (Egypt) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Bags; Costumes; Egypt; Fashion Accessories; Fur Garments; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Guns; Individual Portraits; Studio Photography; Swords & Knives; Women
  - A series of five individual portraits of three women and two girls. Second photograph has parts tinted red. 20.0 x 55.7 cm, 1927; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Arabic Writing; Egypt; Fashion Accessories; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Girls; Hand-colored Photographs / Hand-tinting; Individual Portraits; Jewellery; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Women
  - A series of four individual portraits of men and one presumably missing photo. 18.9 x 54.0 cm, Undated; Unknown (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Mustaches; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Suits
  - A series of five individual portraits of men. 19.2 x 54.3 cm, Undated; Studio Charles, Cairo (Egypt); Studio Photo Ramses, Cairo, Egypt (Box 8, Folder 7)
    Egypt; Fezes / Tarbouches; Furnishings; Gelatin Silver Prints; Individual Portraits; Men; Painted Backdrops; Photographic Prints; Studio Photography; Windows